WES RODGERS

mail:

front-end developer



favorite front-end framework: favorite server-side scripting language: hometown: phone: Angular.js Ruby Los Angeles, Ca 323.854.9438 jwesleyrodgers@gmail.com

"I firmly believe that you will get out of life what you put in. I'm putting in positivity, hardwork, and dedication."

OBJECTIVE

Obtain a full-time a Front-End Developer position, where my passion for building highly functional, beautiful web applications can thrive.

SKILLS

Front-End: Angular.js, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Materialize

Back-End: Ruby, Ruby on Rails (RoR)

Testing: Rspec, Capybara

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, ActiveRecord, MongoDB, Firebase

Version Control: Git, GitHub

Other: Amazon Web Services, OmniAuth(Facebook, Twitter, Google+), Test-Driven Development (TDD), **Heroku**, Pivotal Tracker, Responsive Design, Social Media Marketing, Event Planning and Management, REST API's, Websockets, Fast-learner, Resourceful

PORTFOLIO

<u>Barrett Law</u> (2015) "<u>Barrett Law</u>" (http://www.barrett-law.com) - This site was developed for a law firm located in Simi Valley in collaboration with Thinking2.com

Technologies: Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap

Young Entrepreneurs Association of California (2015) "YEAcal.org" (http://www.yeacal.org) - This site was developed for a high school leadership group in collaboration with Thinking2.com.

Technologies: Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap

#THEJUANFORDANIELLE (2015) "#THEJUANFORDANIELLE" (www.thejuanfordanielle.com) - Basic wedding site Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap, Instagram API

SHREDZILLA (2015) "SHREDZILLA" (www.shredzilla.me) - Platform fitness application (Crossfit meets The Whole Life Challenge) Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Javascript, PostgreSQL, CSS₃, Bootstrap, Heroku, Heroku Scheduler, Git, Github, Social Authentication

Shredzilla the app delivers daily workouts, and challenges as well as a scorecard that tracks the users progress through the Shredzilla fitness program.

<u>Grublt</u> (2015) "<u>Grublt</u>" (www.grub1out.herokuapp.com) - Instagram meets Yelp

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Javascript, PostgreSQL, CSS₃, Bootstrap, Heroku, Git, Github, Social Authentication, Pivotal Tracker GrubIt sought to present a more restaurant friendly Yelp experience by substituting restaurant reviews, for images of the restaurant and menu items with descriptions.

<u>Tic-Tac-Toe</u> (2015) "just <u>Tic Tac Toe</u>" (westttapp.firebaseio.com) – My first production level web application

Technologies: Angular.js, Javasrcript, Firebase, HTML5, CSS3

This was an epic exploration of connecting front-end to back-end. Using vanilla javascript, I created basic game logic that allowed the connection of Angular and Firebase to shine, with their two-way binding, real-time functionality.

RELATED EXPERIENCE

Pop The Pixel (Part-time Contract) – West Hollywood, California

Front-End Developer (September 2015- present)

I am the primary Front-End developer, building beautiful, mobile friendly sites from custom designs approved by the client. I use a combination of **Javascript**, **jQuery**, HTML5, CSS3, and **Bootstrap**, utilizing the Wordpress backend per the client request.

THINKING2 (Part-time Contract) - Simi Valley, California

Front-End Developer (august 2015- present)

Over the past two months, I have been the Front-End developer on six different sites. Successfully delivering pixel perfect, mobile-friendly sites from designs approved by the clients. The primary technologies used are **Javascript**, **jQuery**, **Bootstrap**, HTML5, and Css3

FREELANCER Los Angeles, California

Web Developer (2014- present)

Along with the three web applications listed above, I recently finished a wedding site for a client. As well as, two Big Commerce sites where I used Boostrap, CSS₃, and jQuery to fully resemble the client's official sites. Up next, is a blog for Entertainment Lawyer's.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

PITFIRE PIZZA North Hollywood, California

Assistant General Manager (2010-2015)

- I was the de-facto problem solver for my staff and our guests, as well the debugger of all things computer related.
- I conducted daily stand-ups to discuss restaurant changes, improvements, and goals, while also giving each staff member a moment to communicate about what they were struggling with and excited about at work and in life.
- Created an efficient way to maintain payroll that did not affect guest experience, or server well being.

ACTIVE RIDESHOP Santa Monica, California

Assistant Store Manager (2007-2010)

- I was responsible for many things in this role but what excited me the most was figuring out cool ways to display the new product we received on a daily basis.
- My merchandising style not only helped grow sales, but my store became the staple for merchandising across the company.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY Los Angeles, California (2015)

Web Development Immersive Graduate

12-week accelerated course in Full-Stack Web Development using Agile and Test-Driven Development

AZUSA PACIFIC UNIVERSITY Azusa, California (2001-2005)

Bachelor of Arts (B.A), Communication and Media Studies

